Guide to the Edgar Eugene Robinson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Professional Correspondence Files, 1910-1952
  - (Am - Az), 1930 - 1935 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    American Legislators' Association (aids for law-makers); R.E. Albright; Carl L. Alsberg (graduate students as instructors); invitation to join Pi Gamma Mu; R.E. Swain; International relations; recommendations to Huron College (S. Dakota); minutes of the special committee of the American Association for the Advancement of Science to consider the relations between the social & economic sciences & natural sciences (24 Jan. 1931); Association of American Universities; Henry Anderson; appointment service; R.L. Asquith; series on Stanford in The Argonaut.
  - (Ba - Bi), 1930 - 1935 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    T.A. Bailey (sinking of Lusitania, work in Wash. D.C., request to E.A. Cottrell for funds); Margery Bailey, Mrs. Philip Bancroft; additional material on Bailey (work at Univ. of Washington); J. Earle Baker; Charles A. Barker; goals of citizenship course; T.S. Barclay; recommendation for W.C. Bark; reginald Bell; Carl Becker; C.A. Beard; [A.B. Bender]; Margaret Bennett; Hoover's greeting to John Bender on his 100th birthday; H.H. Bellot; Samuel F. Bemis; Andre A. Beaumont Jr.; citizenship syllabus; Bernard I. Bell.
  - (Bi - Bz), 1930 - 1935 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Robert C. Binkley (Joint Committee on Materials for research); Joseph B. Brown; speaking engagements; J.B. Bowen; H.E. Bourne (editor, American Historical review); letter to C.F. Brand; reid R. Briggs (includes account of 1933 inauguration); Harold R. Bruce; Harold W. Bradley; George G. Bruntz; Lyman Bryson (California Association for Adult Education); Rhodes Scholarship recommendation for Robert Minge Brown; Dudley H. Burney; R. Buchanan; Social Science research Council.
  - (Ca - Ck), 1930 - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    California State Library (Sacramento); restriction of Asiatic immigration; Journal exchange with Univ. of London; What is Happening to the Constitution; California Joint Immigration Committee; California Association for Adult Education (includes special programs); faculty club; letters to A.M. Cathcart (re advantages of quarter system); Lucy W. Adams; California Historical Society; J.L. Christian; Citizens' League on Government & Taxation of Santa Clara County; Census Bureau.
  - (Herbert Hoover's The Challenge to Liberty), 1935 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Ralph Gabriel; W.T. Root; Frederick Merk; F.L. Paxson; R.C. Clark; John P. Pritchett; C.W. Hackett.
  - (Cl - Coq), 1935 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    R.C. Clark; G.T. Robinson; Tracy Coker (includes mention of national & Idaho political situation); Paul H. Clyde (includes Far East trip); E.W. Clement; Dictionary of American Biography (re Stephen M. White); Walter E. Clark; Commonwealth Club of California; letters of introduction for W.H. Cooke; Colonial Dames of America (essay contest); Committee for the Immediate Defense of Constitutional Rights; John R. Commons' birthday fund; Commonwealth Club of California; Tracy Coker.
  - (Cor - Cz), 1930 - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    A.F. Coyle; Frederick Merk (recommending R. Current); R.L. Wilbur; B.F. Culver; George E. Crothers; Hardin Craig (independent study); California Emergency relief Commission; D.E. Cross; E.A. Cottrell; Edward M. Hulme; D.W. Curtis; Albert F. Coyle (loans to deserving students); E.P. Cubberley; Stanford YMCA report for autumn 1929.
  - (D), 1930 - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    J.S. Davis (Social Science research Conference); W.H. Davis (Stanford Press); Edwin Deller (includes mention of current political trends); R.O. DeMonde; Democratic Women Forum; rejected thesis of G. Dickie; Edith Dobie; T.E. Drake; A.A.U.P. survey of college & univ. teaching; C.A. Duniway; L.B. Shippee.
  - (E) (F), 1930 - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    Seba Elridge (texts in college education); E. Ellery; secondary education (Dept. of the Interior); National Committee on research in Secondary Education); R. Elder (exploitation of janitors at Stanford); L.H. Evans; A. Fitzhugh; H.H. Fisher; Max Farrand (includes reference to Woodrow Wilson & Turner letters), letter to Mrs. C.R. Fish; Sidney B. Fay; Carl R. Fish; reference to Sen. Flint (letter to W.R. Flint); Guy S. Ford; H.G. Florcis; M. Fuller; L.W. Fuller; Paul Knaplund; J.F. Willard; W.C. Binkley; C.B. Malone; P.A. Martin (re G. Freyre).
  - (Ga - Gh), 1930 - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    Ralph Gabriel (intellectual history, Stanford summer appointment); to D. Charles Gardner; Charles Gauld III (including reference to great-grandfather's diary); Stephen B. Gavrilovic (possible temporary appointment at Stanford); Ralph Lutz (also concerning Gavrilovic); W.W. Ray; E.M. Gettys.
  - (Gi - Gz), 1930 - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    J.M. Gleason; C.M. Goethe; C. Goodwin (AHA); E. Goodman; Gladys M. Graham; Albert Guerard; summer appointment of Henri Gregoire; disarmament petition; D. Harris (re Gregoire); Guggenheim Foundation; F.G. Guittard.
  - (Ha - Hd), 1930 - 1934 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    recommendation of Clarence Osborn; A.H. Von Hafften; R.C. Haight; C.W. Hackett (invitation to Robinson for seminar on Mexican history); I. Hall; Leo Harvey; critisicm of a David Harris lecture (by Robinson); R.C. Binkley, D. Harris (especially regarding appointment).
  - (He - Ho), 1930 - 1934 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    W.H. Heicher; G. Hinkle; Herbert C. Jones; F. Hichborn (especially re papers in his possession); R.L. Wilbur; C. P. Higby (summer appointment); Charles Hodges; Paul A. Clyde (seeking information on Woodrow Wilson); [F.W. Hirst]; letters to Herbert Hoover (includes mention of John R. McBride manuscript); letter to editor of Saturday review of Literature; J.P. Hoover; Liberalism (by Guido de Ruggiero).
  - (Ho - Hz), 1930 - 1934 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    John P. Hoover (trip to Latin America); J.G. Howes; Glen C. Hoover (proposal for formation of political group); R.L. Wilbur; Charles Hodges (includes reference to The Background of International relations); Edward M. Hulme; P. Hurt (especially re graduate students' research); Huntington Library; more on E.M. Hulme (from Europe).
  - (I), 1930 - 1935 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    A. Guerard; Institut Historique et Heraldique de France; Y. Ichihashi (trip to Japan, Robinson writes of possible 10 percent salary cut, sickness, coming of M. Savelle); 1932 Iron Cross reunion (newsletter includes financial situation of Univ. of Wisconsin); Institute of International relations; Institute for Administrative Officers of Higher Institutions; William S. Gray; Herbert I. Priestly.
  - (J), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    Elizabeth Jackson, Death of H.B. Learned; Durwood Howes; O. S. Johnson; Eliot Jones; Mrs. David S. Jordan; Tribute to D. S. Jordan; R. L. Jones.
  - (Ka - Kk), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    D. L. Kemmerer, rental of cottage: Sept. 1935; John H. Kemble, Modification of Summer Quarter; Grayson Kefauver; William Kirk; R. J. Kerner; H. H. Fisher (re T. B. Kittridge); L. P. Kibby; L. Kirkpatrick.
  - (Kl - Kz), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    J. W. Studebaker (re Hans Kohn); George H. Knoles, Letters to Allan Nevins (1893 Panic); Frank J. Klingberg; Olive Kuntz (re Frank Gilliam); M. Kruse; A. C. Krey.
  - (L), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    Norman F. Coleman (re T. La Fargue); Wolfgang Langewiesche; Richard T. LaPiere, National Council of Geographraphy Teachers; Robert Lee; Mrs. H. B. Learned (re Disposition of H. B. Learned's Books); League of Nations Association; American Council of Learned Societies (Seventh International Congress of Historical Sciences-Warsaw-August 1933); H. B. Learned's Writings (Stanford Press, American Council of Learned Societies); R. F. Swain; F. C. Learned; H. B. Learned (Appointment at Stanford); City Improvement League; R. Lindman; Letter to Mrs. M. Lissner (re California Manuscript Collections); Ralph Lutz (European Trip-Mentions Political Situation, Materials for Hoover Institute, World Almanac, James Van Toor, Survey Studies in American History); J. B. Lockey; R. Lutz (Ph. D. Candidates M.A. Candidates, Advanced Courses, Syllabus and Jewel Funds).
  - (M - Mac), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    Henry M. Madden; Macmillan Co., (reprinting The Foreign Policy of Woodrow Wilson); R. MacFarlane; R. Madsen, Dictionary of American Biography.
  - (Mac - Mar), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    Beverly McAnear (including EER's recommendations for him); Euarts B. Greene; H. O. McCumber; Emily A. McClellan (re Letter Collection of John McClellan); Frank L. McVey, California State Teachers' Association (1930-31 Conventions of Central Coast Section).
  - (Mar - Me), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    T. P. Martin (Including recommendation for Position of National Archivist); P. A. Martin, Commission on National Archives Survey; Royal Marten; Charles Martin (School of Pacific and Oriental Affairs, World Court, National Archives Bill).
  - (Me - N), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    G. D. Merner; J. E. Merrill; Eliot G. Mears; Abe Mellinkoff (Stanford Daily); J. P. Mitchell (Citzenship Course, registration on Unit Basis), Committee on Lower Division Administration; C. I. Millard; R. M. Miller; Mississippi Valley Historical Association; University of California Extension Division; William A. Morris, Speaking Engagements; Motion Picture research Council; recommendation of Mary K. Morris to Key Pittman; Exchange of Letters with W. B. Munro re Julian Huxley, American Association of University Professors (Chapter Letter #5); F. Moulton.
  - (N), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    National Historic Sites; The New School for Social research (Speech on Hitlerism); National Economic League; National Academy of American Literature; C. L. Alsberg; National Student-Faculty Conference (1930); W. Mayo Newhall; Harley Notter; Ray S. Baker (re H. Notter); H. O. Noyes; J. R. Nichols.
  - (O), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    R. Olson, Correspondence re Speech for Oakland Forum; W. P. Ogbun (Analysis of 1938 Presidential Elections).
  - (P - Pl), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    Dwight Palmer; Frederic L. Paxson (Social Science research Conference of the Pacific Coast); J. C. Parish, W. H. Cooke; H. H. Pattee; T. Pedersen; Letter to Frances Perkins Declining Invitation to Conference in San Francisco; R. V. Peel; G. J. Pierce, Milton Lathem Diary; Kate Pinsdorf; Vera Pearson; James D. Phelan.
  - (Pl - Pz), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    recommendations of Mary Purdy; W. Poynter, T. A. Bailey; J. P. Pritchett (Poor Financial Situation at University of North Dakota); Herbert I. Priestly (Acquisition of old newspapers, also re course which he taught at Stanford); M. S. Power, Jr., Speaking Engagements, Princeton University Public Life Course.
  - ( The Presidential Vote: Comment), 1930-35 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    R. L. Wilbur, P. J. Treat, R. C. Brooks, H. C. Hockett, R. C. Fletcher, Brainerd Dyer, Elmer Ellis, Cedric Larson, P. Bradley, The Commonwealth, C. A. Beard, W. E. Dodd, [Dave?], Herbert Hoover, C. O. Paullin, D. C. Roper, N. Van Patten, H. P. Hartkemeier.
  - (R - Ro), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    Charles Rass (Tirade against Economic System); recommendations for H. E. rensch; J. H. Ralston; Earl Ramey, Appointment to Committees on Public Exercises and on Lower Division; Emory Ratcliffe; Kurt F. reinhardt (Inquiry of the School of Letters with regard to the future development of the Department of Graphic Arts); H. E. rensch, United States Society; W. D. Briggs; D. G. rempel; Thomas reed Material (in letter to his daughter, Mrs. A. T. Balentine); W. A. Robinson; Frank D. reeve; Mary B. Ritter, T. M. DeMotte.
  - (Ro - Rz), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    EER's 1934-35 Publications, D. C. Roper (After the Decision); Elmo A. Robinson (Are American Colleges Teaching Radicalism?), Speaking Engagements, A. Rose, Concern with Quality of Independent Study Students, History Department and Students; Ralph S. Roberts, Univ. of Iowa History Department Newsletters; U.C./Stanford History Departments joint dinner; W. T. Root (Comments on Depression, Also Summer at Stanford); Beardsley Ruml (Each According to his Own Experience); George Russell Lecture Tour; G. A. Johnston Ross.
  - (S - Scho), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    Max Savelle as Head of Committee on History of Western Civilization; M. Savelle (Including Shelburne Papers, Possible Acquisition of Early Newspapers, Filming of Early Newspapers, Correspondence re his Appointment at Stanford), Speaking Engagements, W. L. Westermann; B. E. Schmitt.
  - (Scho - Si), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    Victoria Schuck, Constitution of the School of Social Sciences; Martha N. Schofield (Including copy of letter written during Civil War describing conditions in Union Army occupying the South); Charles Seymour G. Showerman; Louis M. Sears; Samuel M. Shortridge (re Senate Executive Journal); J. A. Sellards (re B. H. Sumner, James W. Thompson); B. F. Shambaugh (re Seventh Commonwealth Conference).
  - (Si - St), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    E. O. Sisson; Laura E. Simpson; E. D. Adams (re O. C. Skipper); C. N. Spinks, Note referring to Manuscript Collections.
  - (St - Sz), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    E. P. Stickney; T. A. Storey (Program of Professional Education in Hygiene and Physical Education); Dick Strouse; Student relief Payroll; Stanford University Press; Carl Stephenson (Summer Appointment); J. E. Wallace Sterling; Henry W. Stuart; Stanford Christian Association; David H. Stevens, Motion Picture research Council; R. E. Swain (Jordan Memorial Service, Travel Funds, Honor Code).
  - (T), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    Harold F. Taggart; Harold Thompson; William W. Tinsley; Sinclair Trimble; P. J. Treat, recommendation to Humboldt State Teachers' College, Columbia Teachers' College Bulletin on Education; reginald G. Trotter.
  - (U), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    Stanford University Press; L. D. Upson.
  - (V), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    R. W. Van Alstyne (History of Western Civilization at Chico State), S. Martin ( Wasp-S.F. Weekly), Historic American Buildings Survey; N. Van Patten ( Memorias de la Alta California Escrita for Sr. Don Antonio Maria Ozio, B. McAnear; George Vernadsy (Summer appointment), H. H. Fisher.
  - (W - Wen), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    E. E. Walker; James T. Watkins, IV, Speaking Engagements; H. G. Warren; H. E. Bolton (re B. C. Weber); O. H. Wedel.
  - (Wen - Wi), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    R. White; W. L. Westermann; Edward White (Extensive correspondence, especially re Dissertation work, Employment, Personal Experiences); L.B. Shippee, Course on History of Stanford (Robinson-Whitely).
  - Course in University History., 1931 - (Box 8, Folder 70a)
  - (Wi - Wo), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    Oscar O. Winther; R. L. Wilbur (Visit of Prince and Princess Kaya (?), Changing of Citizenship requirements; Work of Junior Dept. Members, Memorandum re period April 6-April 29, 1934, Constitution Course, Citizen Course); 1933 Crop & Livestock Loans, Max Farrand.
  - (Wo - Wz), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    Gordon Wright; Arthur F. Wright, Department-Majors Lecture Series; F. C. Wooton; Paul Knaplund (re Edward White and others); Dorothea Wyatt; David E. Wynne.
  - (XYZ), 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    Youth Anti-War Conference; Fred G. Young.
  - (A), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    M. Appel; R. E. Albright; Carl Alsberg (re retsu Kiyosawa), Honor Code; P. B. Albright, Deaths of W. M. Newhall and T.T.C. Gregory.
  - (B), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    William Bark; Harold W. Bradley; Russell Buchanan; William K. Boyd; Dana M. Barbour; Gray C. Boyce; D. H. Burney; Albert E. Boynton (Anti-Communist Sentiments); H. E. Bolton, Speaking Engagements.
  - (C), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    Merle Curti; Christian Science Monitor; Tracy Coker; R. C. Clark; California Safety Council; Colonial Dames Essay Contest; Albert Coyle; Kenneth C. Cole.
  - (COMMONWEALTH CLUB) Constitution and By-Laws (Box 9, Folder 77)
    Albert E. Boynton, C. C. Young, E. A. Cottrell, Committee Chairmanships, A. C. Roberts, Max Thelen, Proposed Amendments/By-Laws, S. C. May, Does Democracy Need a Bulwark?
  - (Commonwealth Club, 1932-36) (Box 9, Folder 78)
    Max Thelen, Causes of Wars and Population Pressure, James M. Beck, Concern with Traffic Safety, 1932 Literature Medal Contest; William H. Waste, F. V. Keesling, H. C. Rowley, C. C. Young, Invitations to H. C. Hoover, R. H. Fouke, A. E. Boynton, Will C. Wood, Stuart R. Ward, George W. Dowrie (The Present Banking Situation in the U.S.)
  - (D), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    Thomas E. Drake, Edith Dobie, W.E. Dodd.
  - (E-F), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    Luther H. Evans, F. A. Bushee (re Emery Fast), C. H. Fish.
  - (G), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    recommendation of John Gange, A. Guerard, D. C. Gardner.
  - (H), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 82)
    Arthur G. Kennedy, Statement concerning the public forum project, Lt. C. Hockett, C. H. Hunter, Harvard Torcentenary conference of Arts and Sciences, Hugh Harvey, David Harris (seeking relief from administrative duties), John G. Howes, Edward A. Hoyt, R. L. Wilbur (Memorandum of conversation with Senator H. C. Jones and Franklin Hichborn), H. C. Jones (re manuscript material to be acquired by Haynes Foundation), Charles Hodges, Letter to H. Hoover (re American Democracy), Lauder Hodges.
  - In Praise of Newspapers (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - (I - K), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 84)
    R. B. Kleinsmid, Mrs. David S. Jordan, F. J. Klingberg (re B. McAnear and others), J. Kemble, recommendation of George Knoles.
  - (L), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 85)
    A. J. Lyrd, Sidney Long, John Marshall, Letters re Thomas LaFargue.
  - (M), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 86)
    P. A. Martin, Motion Picture research Council, Memorial Hall, J. D. Mitchell, Frederick Merk, John Marshall.
  - (Mc), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    Beverly McAnear, Edward McMahon.
  - (N), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    Harley Notter, Charles Norman, National Economic League.
  - (O - P), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    Clarence Osborn, D. L. Palmer, J. P. Pritchett, E. L. Paxson.
  - (Q - R), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 90)
    F. L. Paxson (re M. I. Rostovtzeff), Earl Ramey.
  - (S), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    Nelson Spinks (re Stay in Japan), Cordell Hull (Telegrams re Max Savelle), Social Science magazine, San Francisco World Affairs Assembly, Speaking Engagements, H. M. Smyth, R. E. Swain, David H. Stevens.
  - (T), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    Harold Temperely (summer appointment), Harold F. Taggart, F. W. Thomas.
  - (U - V), 1935-36 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    Detroit Bureau of Government research, T. A. Bailey (re R. Van Alstyne), In Praise of Newspapers.
  - (W), 1935-36 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    S. J. Worsley, Oscar O. Winther, Gordon Wright, Arthur F. Wright, R. L. Wilbur, B. C. Nelson, H. N. M. Winton, W. S. Ament, Letter to R. L. Wilbur on occasion of completion of E.E. R.'s 25th year at Stanford, Princeton History Alumni letter (6/26), H. E. Bolton, Edward White, Lynn White, Jr., E. McMahon, H. M. Woodward (Public Opinion and World Peace), James T. Watkins.
  - (XYZ), 1935-36 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - (A), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    R. E. Albright, R. C. Clark.
  - (B), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    T. A. Bailey, Letter to R. L. Wilbur re Committee on Public Exercises, B. L. Borough, C. A. Barker, D. H. Burney, W. M. Barber, H. E. Bolton, G. G. Bruntz, D. Barbour, Comment on S. F. News Editorial, G. E. Bodle (re Edward Maslin Hulme Society), Big Ten University Club.
  - (C), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    W. Chamberlin, B. F. Culver, R. G. Cleveland, W. H. Cooke, Arthur C. Cole, (WPA Cleveland Newspaper Digest Project), Tracy Coker.
  - (D), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 99)
    S. E. Davis, R. L. Wilbur, Edith Dobie, Memorandum concerning Bernard De Voto, Dictionary of American History, Death of Edwin Deller.
  - (E - F), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 100)
    Guy S. Ford, Emery Fast, L. W. Fuller, Elizabeth Forbes, C. H. Fisher.
  - (G), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 101)
    John Gange, Ralph H. Gabriel, Charles Gauld.
  - (H), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 102)
    David Harris, E. W. Hardington, John D. Hicks, Hazel D. Hansen (Archeological work in Greece), John P. Hoover.
  - (I - K), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 103)
    Frank J. Klingberg, Lingnan exchange students of North America.
  - (L), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 104)
    Thomas LaFargue, Ralph Lutz, Louis P. Lochner, Elinor Kahn, Aline Lissner, A. J. Lynd.
  - (M), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 105)
    W. E. Marsh, Frederick Merk, S. B. Morris, G. W. Adams, Beverly McAnear, Marie McSpadden, R. L. Wilbur.
  - (N - P), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 106)
    National Cyclopedia of American Biography, D. C. Poole, letters re Harley Notter, Pacific Coast Branch (American Historical Society), F. L. Paxson, Dwight L. Palmer.
  - (R), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 107)
    J. F. Rippy, A. C. Roberts, W. T. Root, Angelo Ross, (opening of Golden Gate Bridge).
  - (S), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 108)
    J. E. W. Sterling, Stanford Fund, William S. Hopkins (Possible sale of EER's house), Max Savelle (Independent study library), Louis M. Sears, C. C. Young, University Day dinner, Suggestions for Stanford Associates `Large Donors solicitation program, Bernadotte Schmitt, C. N. Spinks, More Max Savelle.
  - (T - V), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 109)
    Borel Collection Library, N. Van Patten, R. C. Buley.
  - (W), 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 110)
    History of Western Civilization, (Letter to R. L. Wilbur), Arthur F. Wright, Edward White, Harry Winton, H. G. Warren, Dorothea Wyatt, R. L. Wilbur, Lynn White, James P. Weter, James T. Watkins, Oscar O. Winther, E. A. Cottrell.
  - (A), 1937-38 (Box 10, Folder 111)
    Henry M. Adams, San. Alderson, Allied Youth, K. R. Brown, Alumni Conference Committee, Election to AHA Nomination Committee, M. Appel, American Association of University Professors (report of [Stanford] Projects Committee) M. N. Alderman.
  - (B), 1937-38 (Box 10, Folder 112)
    Autumn plans for Western Civilization, Charles A. Barker, William C. Bark, recommendation of Dana Barbour, Russell Buchanan, Violet Barbour (re AHA Presidential succession), E. McMahon, F. M. Barrows, H. Hale Bellot, T. S. Barclay, Union of California Citizens, J. H. Meyer Endowment, rene Binet, G. C. Boyce, S. F. Bemis, Dana M. Barbour, reginald Bell, Robert C. Binkley (Joint Committee for Materials on research).
  - (C), 1937-38 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    E. W. Clement, Alfred Crofts, Tracy Coker, Manuel Cardozo, E. A. Cottroll, William Chislett Jr., E. P. Cubberley, Hardin Craig, P. J. Treat, W. T. Cross, Colonial Dames of America.
  - (D), 1937-38 (Box 10, Folder 114)
    W. H. Davis (Stanford Press), Monroe E. Deutsch, G. A. Ditz, Edith Dobie, C. E. Diehl, N. F. D'Evelyn T. M. DeMotte, C. A. Duniway.
  - (E), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    English - Speaking Union
  - (F), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 116)
    Helen D. Fisher, Max Farrand, Letters re Emery Fast, Mrs. C. Fremantle (includes comments on international student exchange), E. Forbes, Institute of International Education, Golden Spike, Founders' Day, M. Savelle.
  - (G), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 117)
    Western Literary Messenger, John Gange, International Goodwill Congress, Richard E. Guggenhime, A. Guerard, Arthur Linkletter (Golden Gate International Exposition), Ralph H. Gabriel, J. W. Gerard (Increasing foreign travel to the U. S.), Stanford Session on the History of the Americas.
  - (H), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 118)
    [Hoover handwritten letter (?)], J. R. Hewitt, Francis H. Herrick (Pacific Coast Branch, AHA), James L. Hagerty, Hazel Hansen, Franklin Hichborn (re correspondence in his hands).
  - (I), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 119)
    International Goodwill Congress, Institute of International Education, Interfraternity Alumni Conference, [Y. Ichihashi (?)].
  - ( Independent Study at Stanford) R. L. Wilbur, Distribution of Complimentary Copies., 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - (J), 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 121)